# Sinclair Akoto London | 07481790498 sinclair.python@gmail.com

#### **Summary**

I am a capable, enthusiastic and confident individual, with strong communication skills. Computer literate and self motivated, with a committed and hardworking approach. Able to work under pressure and to tight deadlines, both on my own initiative and in a team environment, with proven experience in a corporate environment. I also have excellent attention to detail coupled with strong organisation skills.

## **Key Skills**

- Python / Flask (beginning level): conditional logic, if statements, while loops, for loops, lists, dictionaries, concept of object orientated programming.
- Dart / Flutter (entry/beginner level): understanding of Stateful & Stateless widgets, scaffolds, containers, creating onPressed callbacks, refactoring code, creating custom widgets, releasing apps onto both iOS and Android platforms.
- Highly self motivated but also a team player, with a willingness to learn and adapt; including constantly thinking of new ideas.

## **Key Achievements**

- EasyCHEF! I built my first program in less than 6 weeks; the program is deployed locally from my laptop. EasyCHEF! Is a simple program that uses dictionaries, lists and functions to complete its objective. EasyCHEF! Prompts the user to select one ingredient from a list of proteins, carbohydrates and vegetables. The program then searches for the matching 3 ingredients located in the food bank, and returns a recipe once a match is found. If the user doe not like the first choice, they can prompt the program to find a different recipe but with the same 3 main ingredients.
- This has also been developed into a web app: <a href="https://www.bondrobotics.tech/easychef">https://www.bondrobotics.tech/easychef</a>
- My Digital Business Card using Dart & Flutter, I developed a digital business card. The aim of the app is to provide quick and easy access to the business contact details, location and website all with a touch of a button. You can find out more information about the app on <a href="https://www.bondrobotics.tech/mdb">https://www.bondrobotics.tech/mdb</a>
- Young Spenders App I designed, built and released an app for Young Spenders to promote healthy financial habits for young people (aged 25 and younger). The motive of the app is to allow quick and easy access to their website; with unique features such as a platform where users can login/register to speak to an advisor from Young Spender, and also share the app easily amongst others by scanning the QR code.

## **Education**

2008 - 2010 Manchester Metropolitan University - Film & Television Broadcast Media

2006 - 2008 Stockport College - National Diploma Media: Moving Images

1998 - 2003 Wright Robinson Sports College

## **Qualifications**

- SIA Door Supervision & CCTV badge
- Foundation Degree Film & Broadcast Media
- National Diploma Media Moving Images

## **Employment History**

Security Officer - Deloitte August 2018 - Present

- Access control, concierge service, interior patrols, ensuring public safety
- Incident reporting
- Ensuring team members are allocated in the correct positions

## Security Officer - Willis Towers Watson April 2016 - August 2018

- Access control, CCTV patrols, control room duties, hotel concierge service
- Cover supervisor role & training new operatives on site
- Paying attention to detail and ensuring public safety

# **Lighting Technician - Film Freelancer** May 2010 - August 2018

- Setting up lighting equipment on a film set, creating character and dimension to the scene
- Making sure the lighting set up Is safe and not hazardous for the people on set
- Being able to work with a large amount of people from different backgrounds/cultures, working effectively to get the job done